Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Cadillac, Mich.) records, 1876-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Cadillac, Mich.) records 1876-1999
First Presbyterian Church (Cadillac, Mich.).
2 linear feet
86825 Ba 2
Cadillac, Michigan Presbyterian church established in 1872; history; governance records; records of Sunday School; women’s organizations; and scattered other records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the church (donor no. 5505 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Society of Clam Lake, later named the First Presbyterian Church of Cadillac, was established in 1872 and built its first church in 1873. Fire destroyed this facility in 1903. For two years, member met in the Opera House for services. In 1905, a new church building was completed.
The records of the First Presbyterian Church of Cadillac, Michigan includes a history; records of the original church, the First Presbyterian Society of Clam Lake; minutes of the session of the church and of the board of trustees; and minutes of the annual meetings. In addition, the record group contains record books of the various women's organizations, including the Church Women's Association, the Crescent Circle, the Ladies Aid Society, and the Women's Missionary Society.
Subjects:
Cadillac (Mich.); United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.--Michigan--Cadillac.
- History
  - "The First Century, 1872-1972" by Betty Warren Best, 1972 (Box 1)
- Governance
  - Records of First Presbyterian Society of Clam Lake, March 1876-June 1895 (Box 1)
    (church later reformed as First Presbyterian Church of Cadillac)
  - Minutes of the Session
    - August 1883-March 1937 (Box 1)
    - April 1937-March 1955 (Box 1)
    - April 1955-January 1966 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Board of Trustees
    - 1891-1921 (Box 1)
    - April 1940-1953 (Box 1)
    - 1954-February 1963 (Box 1)
    - March 1963-December 1969 (Box 1)
  - Board of Deacons financial records, 1956-1971 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Annual Meetings
    - February 1898-January 1954 (Box 1)
    - January 1955-1970 (also annual reports, January 1955-1970) (Box 1)
- Church education
  - Sunday School records, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Records of Christian Education Committee, 1956-1967 (Box 2)
- Women's organizations
  - Church Women's Association records
    - 1948-1955 (Box 2)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 2)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Crescent Circle records, 1950-1961 (Box 2)
  - Ladies Aid Society minutes, 1932-1947 (Box 2)
  - Secretary's book of the Women's Missionary Society secretary's books, 1880-1939, 9 volumes (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Annual reports, 1989-1999 (lacking 1996) (Box 2)
  - Membership directories, 1990-1997 (Box 2)